Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Escape
That Gundam...
Char!
Who's that?!
Concentrate fire to starboard.
Fraw Bow.
How are the Guncannon and Guntank?
They're still active.
Approaching entrance to enemy base!
Attacking from outside isn't
getting us anywhere...!
I won't let Mr. Kai have all the fun!
Dammit! I was the first one who landed!
I warned you...
Gundam...!
You can't attack from all directions
when I'm this close! Hey, Char?!
What?
Why did you get Lalah involved?!
Lalah was never meant to be a warrior!
Char!
Hey! Snap out of it!
Don't you die on me!
Leave the rest to the mobile suits!
That Gundam pilot..."Amuro", was it?
What do I do?
How can I beat that Newtype...?
Lalah. Please tell me.
What should I do?
Shut down the engines immediately!
Cut off the engines. Mirai!
Yes, sir!
We're touching down.
I'll leave it to you. Tell all hands
to prepare for hand-to-hand combat!
Sir!
The controls, they're...!
Watch your surroundings!
We don't know where
the enemy will come from!
Both the White Base engines are blown!
Oh no! Is everyone okay?!
Tell Kai and Hayato to cover us!
Yes, sir!
Fraw Bow, get a sidearm.
Yes, sir.
Where are you, Char?!
That wasn't it?!
Gundam!
D-Damn Char!
It's not over!
I've only lost the main camera!
The Zeong's been shot down!
Identification signal canceled!
The Red Comet has fallen from the heavens.
N Field, no response!
S Field, no response! What?! Missiles?!
Send ammo to Block 24 of W Field!
Snakel, Snakel!
If the Gundam pilot has developed
exceptionally because he's a Newtype...
...then perhaps this was inevitable.
Don't you think?
Yes. Your Excellency!
Surrender this base
15 minutes after my escape.
But, ma'am...
I have to go while Granada and
the homeland have fighting strength left.
But escaping at this point would be
almost impossible, ma'am...
As long as I survive, Zeon is not lost.
What will happen to me after we surrender?
I'll get you back in a prisoner exchange.
Right.
Get my ship ready.
Right away, ma'am.
This place is crawling with the enemy!
Enemy ground troops are coming!
All hands, counter with bazookas and rifles!
Even Char must realize the truth...
It's the Zabi family
that needs to be brought down!
Why's he getting in the way?
Char...
He's here...!
I believe I now have the ability
to defeat the true enemy.
I can sense the Zabi family leader is here.
You may have received
those powers from Lalah...
You should be grateful.
You're the one that drew Lalah into the war!
If you can't forgive that,
you're misguided, Amuro.
Wh-What?!
If not for the war, Lalah never
would have awakened as a Newtype.
That's just an excuse!
But it's the correct point of view.
Come any closer and I'll shoot!
Newtypes like yourself are
too dangerous right now...
I will kill you.
You idiot!
You call that "covering the White Base"?!
Hand-to-hand combat, huh...
Where is everyone?
Brother...!
The enemy's all over the place out there!
Send us a Dom company!
Just one Zanzibar isn't enough!
You can't be serious!
We have no intention of dying here!
Send us escorts, even if they're just Zakus!
Is there a delay?
I apologize.
Make them hurry!
Don't let the other soldiers figure things out.
The company commander's
in trouble in Block 24!
They've begun ground combat?
Up ahead...
It's because you're the strongest soldier!
Isn't the true enemy the Zabi family?!
Not in my case!
Do you have any idea why I lured you here?
Because you figured that a Newtype
has to use their body like an ordinary person!
Right. Even a Newtype must
be trained for physical skills.
That's your theory!
Stop it, Amuro! Stop it, brother!
You two don't have to fight each other!
Just because there's a war going on
doesn't mean you two have to...!
What's that?
Lalah just told me...
...that Newtypes aren't meant to be
tools for destroying each other.
In the battlefield, they're powerful weapons.
That's just the way it is.
But you're a Newtype yourself!
Stop this! Both of you...
Amuro! Are you all right?!
Artesia...
Please, brother! Stop this!
You haven't any reason to hate Amuro!
If I can't accept him as my enemy,
I have to get him when I have the chance.
I thought your enemy was the Zabi family?!
Destroying that family is no longer
my top priority, Artesia...
Once Zeon is no more,
we will enter the age of Newtypes.
If young Amuro can understand
what I'm trying to say...
Then become my comrade-in-arms.
It would make Lalah happy, too.
What?!
Brother! How could you even suggest that...
Brother! Is your forehead wounded...?
If it weren't for this helmet, I'd be dead.
Mobile Suit
I knew Lady Kycilia would be escaping.
I had wanted to escort her myself.
But unfortunately...
Captain, perhaps you could...
Don't worry. I'll protect
Her Excellency on your behalf.
Thank you, sir...
The rumors of burns on your face
were not true, it seems...
The air here's getting pretty thin.
Get out now, Artesia.
But what will you do, brother?
I've realized that I can't just
let a Zabi go free, after all.
I'm going to settle the score.
Casval...
You're an adult already.
Forget about this war.
Become a good woman.
Young Amuro is calling for you.
Amuro is...?
Where's Lady Kycilia?!
She's about to take off, sir!
Salamis approaching from above!
We'll take off at once!
Down on the floor if you don't have a seat!
10! 9!
Garma, here's a farewell present.
I know you'll get along with your sister.
Is that Char?!
It's no good...
I... I can't return to the others anymore.
And... if I did... if... I did make it...
My brother couldn't have...!
D-Dammit...
Is this... the end for me...?
I might make it...!
But I wonder...
What about the White Base crew?
And Ms. Sayla?
Am I going to join Lalah?
Newtypes shouldn't be killing each other.
Huh?
Y-You're right. What should I do?
I can play with you anytime, Amuro.
Lalah...!
You know that it's true.
I can see them! Everyone!
Look! You can see things, Amuro.
M-Ms. Sayla! Stand up!
Get up now!
Amuro?! Is that you?!
...But... I don't know where I am!
I should go straight ahead...?
That's right...
And after you've gone 500 meters,
make a 90 degree left turn.
After 500 meters...
Seal off hatch 16!
Yes, sir!
Amuro?!
We'll all die if we don't abandon ship...?
Seal off the hatch!
We don't have any allies left over there!
Y-Yes, ma'am!
Amuro?!
Yes. You're right.
I'll have them prepare the launches!
Amuro?!
My dear Fraw.
The next time the firing stops,
you can run through safely.
Amuro, it's you. Where are you?
Go to the launches! Got it?!
When I start running, you run too. Got it?
Okay!
Argh! They're all aiming at the White Base!
This ship stands out too much!
Did you hear that?
Yeah. It's Amuro.
He says we should retreat now!
I agree.
The Federation Forces seem to be winning.
If they're winning,
we should be okay to retreat.
C'mon!
The White Base...!
Ms. Sayla! Over here!
Sayla!
We've got you!
Kai!
Right. It looks good. Let's take them out.
Roger!
The White Base...
The White Base is... going down...
If Amuro hadn't called out to us...
...those flames would have enveloped us.
A-Are you telling me
Amuro isn't on this launch?!
Bright?!
No, he's not. Sayla, you and Mirai
would be able to hear Amuro better than me.
What?
Sayla. You're the daughter of Zeon...
I'm sure you're closer to a Newtype.
Please, search for Amuro...!
But... But... How do I do it?
I have no idea...!
Amuro's the only one missing. Where is he?
H-How can I possibly know that...?
We heard Amuro's voice just now, right?
Yeah!
I could hear him so clearly
until I got to the White Base...
Amuro...
Human beings can't
change themselves so conveniently...
They can't...
Yeah! A little to the right!
Kikka!
Yeah! Right!
Okay! Now straight forward!
What's going on?! You three...!
- Yeah! This way! This way! Just do it!
- This way! It's okay!
You're almost outside!
Amuro?!
Can you tell?!
Wh-Where is he?!
Ready?!
4! 3! 2! 1!
Zero!
Amuro!!
Wh-Where is everyone?
I'm sorry...
I still do have a place to go home to...
And nothing could make me happier!
You'll understand, won't you...?
I can go to see you anytime, Lalah.
Universal Century 0080.
After this battle...
...a peace treaty was concluded...
...between the Earth Federation Government
and the Republic of Zeon.
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...